

Janick Weberpals, RPh, Ph.D. Health Data Scientist

Born 1989 in Germany, Current location: Boston, MA

janickweberpals.github.io

+1 (857) 381-7865

linkedin.com/in/weberpals

janick.weberpals@me.com

About me ———

I'm a healthcare data scientist with 8+ years of experience in the design and analysis of large healthcare databases studies in both industry and academia. I'm passionate about the integration of various data modalities (EHR/EMR, imaging, NLP, claims) using deep learning to solve real-world problems in healthcare and causal inference. In addition, I have deep domain knowledge in the fields of cancer and cardiovascular diseases. I have (co-) authored 20+ peer-reviewed methodological and clinical publications and received several awards.

Skills ———

Medical coding standards (ICD, etc.)

Python, Tensorflow, Keras

ETEX, Markdown, Quarto

HPC, SLURM, Unix

SOL

SAS

Education

2018-2020 Postdoctoral Fellowship Data Science, Roche Innovation Center, Germany Deep learning on electronic health record (EHR) data

2015-2018 Ph.D. Epidemiology Medical Faculty, Heidelberg University, Germany

Graduated with Summa cum laude honors

2015-2018 **Board certification** Bavarian Chamber of Pharmacists, Munich, Germany Specialized Pharmacist in Drug Information

2010-2015 Registered Pharmacist College of Pharmacy, Marburg University, Germany Pharmaceutical Sciences (PharmD equivalent)

Professional Experience

2022-Instructor in Medicine Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA Faculty at Harvard Medical School leading innovative projects utilizing Machine/Deep learning to leverage routinely collected healthcare data (EHR/EMR, imaging, NLP, claims) to study and generate highquality comparative effectiveness and safety of medical interventions.

2022-Investigator Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, MA, USA Working on NIH and FDA-funded projects to leverage large, federated healthcare databases for medical evidence generation.

2020-2022 **Data Scientist** Hoffmann-La Roche/Genentech, Basel, Switzerland Awarded "Exceptional Performance" in 2021. Led and collaborated in cross-functional teams to implement and validate ML/NLP algorithms and real-world database studies which supported and expedited clinical teams with regulatory drug applications in oncology and neuroscience. Contributed to R package development which increased speed and validity of real-world evidence projects.

2018-2020 Postdoctoral Fellow in Deep Learning on EHR Roche, Munich, Germany Implemented deep learning methods to analyze large electronic health record (EHR) databases which supported protocol design and strategic decision making in single-arm clinical trials.

2015-2018 **Doctoral Researcher** German Cancer Research Center, Heidelberg, Germany Analysis of large oncological database linkages by partnering with international cancer registries which resulted in 14 high-impact publications used for national public health & cancer survival surveillance.

2014-2015 **Research Scholar** University of Florida, Gainesville, FL, USA Contributed to a multidisciplinary project to develop a *predictive* risk model to identify and prevent adverse events among hospitalized patients. The model was implemented and tested in a few US hospitals.

Selected Awards & Honors

2018 Stephan-Weiland Award (German Society for Epidemiology)

2018 Advancement Award for best Ph.D. thesis in Epidemiology (German

Association for Medical Informatics, Biometry and Epidemiology)

2017 Poster Award (Helmholtz International Graduate School)

2016 & 17 International Society for Pharmacoepidemiology (ISPE) Scholarship

Selected publications (full list: janickweberpals.github.io/publications)

Weberpals J, Becker T, Schmich F, Ruettinger D, Theis FJ, Bauer-Mehren A. Deep learning-based propensity scores for confounding control in comparative effectiveness research: a large-scale real-world data study. **Epidemiology** (2021).

Loureiro H, Becker T, Bauer-Mehren A, Ahmidi N, Weberpals J. Artificial Intelligence for Prognostic Scores in Oncology: a benchmarking study. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence (2021).